Rajendra Kumar

17/2-B Saraswati Vihar Colony,
Sector -17, Indira Nagar,
Lucknow – 226016, UP, India
+91 9718100259, +918287212458
raajendra.kumar07@gmail.com
http:/linkedin.com/in/rajendra-kumar-9b550159 in

Python developer 4 years programming experience and Java Technical Lead with 7 years of strong programming experience in developing applications using Core Java, J2EE, JSP, Servlet technologies. Working knowledge of Python and Hadoop with B.Tech. and M.Tech. in (Computer Science & Engineering).

Skills

- Python, Django
- Core Java
- J2EE, JSP, Servlets

- SQL, MySQL, Oracle 11g
- Spring, Hibernate

Experience

APRIL 2020 - CURRENT

Python Developer/Self, Freelancing, Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh

Technology Stack - Python3.8, Django, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript,

Description — Entry level Python developer with proven ability to function with little or no oversight. Highly adept at analysis and problem solving. Proficient in Windows, Mac OS, and Linux with limited working knowledge of Unix.

Responsibilities – Edited scripts looking for bugs. Wrote scripts and worked with API's for IoT devices. Leveraged behave methodologies on projects. Contributed to open source on Behave community as Test Developer.

JAN 2020 - APRIL 2020

Java Team Lead/PETROLEUMSOFT LIMITED, Noida, India

Technology Stack - Core Java, J2EE, Spring boot, JSP, MySQL, Tomcat Server, and Net Beans 6.9.1 IDE

Description — Petroleumsoft is a leading simulation developer and service provider to the oil & gas industry. Specialized in the supply of technology for the analysis and optimization of downhole chemical treatments (such as matrix acidization, scale inhibition, and fracturing) and enhanced oil recovery (EOR) **Responsibilities** — Leading a team of 10 members for software development of numerical simulation, analysis and optimization of acid stimulation, hydraulic fracturing, production optimization, and EOR.

SEP 2017 - JAN 2020

Sr. Software Developer (JAVA)/MCS GEOTECH (P) LTD., Lucknow, India

Technology Stack – Core Java, J2EE, JSP, Servlet, JavaScript, Struts 2.0, MySQL, Tomcat Server, and Net Beans 6.9.1 IDE

Description – e-Government/e-Governance applications for government departments at the States, Districts, and Blocks (Nagar Palika/Panchayat), facilitating improvement in government services, wider transparency, promoting decentralized planning and management, resulting in better efficiency and accountability to the common people.

Responsibilities – Design and implementing new methodologies for e-Government/e-Governance applications. After finalization of the design with several rounds of discussions with govt. officials, applications were designed with the latest data inputs from various departments/offices of the region using the latest technology.

DEC 2015 - AUG 2017

JAVA Trainer / Developer / STUCORNER IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd. – Delhi, India

Environment – Core Java, J2EE, JSP, Servlet, JavaScript, Struts 2.0 & Spring, Hibernate, Oracle.

Description — Training of Entry Level candidates in web designing and programming technologies and working on academic projects with students.

Responsibilities – Technical training, writing, course development, instructional design, and resource coordination.

SEPTEMBER 2008 – MARCH 2012

SOFTWARE CONSULTANT/ PERFECT DENTAL EQUIPMENT (P) LTD - LUCKNOW, UP

Environment –JSP, HTML, Java Scripts, MySQL, NetBeans, MS Access

Responsibilities- Building and updating website of the Organization, ERP Management and IT support.

Education

Master of Technology (2012 - 2014)/Galgotias University, Greater Noida, India

Computer Science & Engineering

Bachelor of Technology (2004 - 2008)/College of Engineering, Roorkee, India

Computer Science & Engineering

REFERENCES

FarhanKhan

(Reporting Manager)
Perfect Dental Equipment
+91-9935563678
farhanmskhan@gmail.com

Rameshwar M Paswan

(Director)
Petroleumsoft Limited
+47 94432969

Rameshwar.paswan@petroleumsoft.co.uk

DECLARATION

I declare hereby that the information furnished above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.